SIMONE SCHNEEBERG

(917) 828 5437 simone.m.schneeberg@gmail.com github.com/sschneeberg.schneeberg.com Washington, DC

Early career full stack developer with an adept problem solving ability, garnered from a mixed background of creative arts and engineering. More than one year of experience in project management, team leadership, and coordination.

RECENT PROJECTS

Pest Damage Report (A Bug Tracker App), MERN Stack Web Application

December 2020

- Lead team of four to create full stack application in ten days, Maintained group repository and development schedule
- Spearheaded back end api and database development in Express with MongoDB, Implemented Socket.io functionality
- Instated user authentication with tiered permissions to allow multifunctional use of the app with varied api access

Tracker App, Express Web Application

December 2020

- Designed personalized, neutral period tracker with focus on baseline functionality and user designated priorities
- Managed an eight model SQL database, implementing both the Sequelize ORM and raw SQL queries
- Organized project into controllers, views, and specialized middleware to maintain DRY and MVC strategies

Fruitris, Client Side Javascript Game

November 2020

- In one week, designed an enhanced Tetris-like game using HTML Canvas and Javascript DOM manipulation
- Implemented MVC strategies to efficiently execute and track gameplay
- Leveraged Javascript's asynchronous functionality to simulate physics and control game logic

Automatic Mixer, Senior Capstone

September - December 2019

- Worked on a team of 5 to own product development cycle from market research to mechanical analysis
- Optimized final design as team lead for design analysis phase including QFD, DFA/DFM, and FMEA processes
- Contributed dozens of detailed sketches to facilitate conversation with team members and advisors
- Oversaw creation of all engineering drawings from 3D Solidworks model

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Remote

Oct 2020 - Present

Software Engineering Fellow

- Tackled daily MVP assignments, covering full stack development of web applications
- Completed and deployed three, week-long projects involving the ideation and creation of web apps from scratch
- Aided other cohort members with the understanding of new concepts, took lead in pair programming exercises

SKA Custom Robots and Machines, Washington, DC

July 2020 - Present

Senior Coordinator

- Mobilized stalled website development within one week as acting project manager working with a contractor
- Slashed time spent on project tracking by 50% through implementing Salesforce to Quickbooks Integrations
- Initialized new strategies for networking and increasing sales in the newly virtual landscape of industry events

Studio Theatre, Washington, DC

July 2019 - June 2020

Assistant Technical Director/Apprentice

- Trimmed costs to fit within \$6000 budget by ideating alternatives without sacrificing any design elements
- Engineered and drafted technical drawings optimized for efficient use of construction time and materials
- Collaborated across departments and worked closely with designers to ensure full execution of creative vision

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University, Carnegie Institute of Technology, Pittsburgh, PA

BS, Mechanical Engineering with University Honors May 2019

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive (Remote), Washington, DC

January 2021

SKILLS

- Languages and Databases: Javascript/Node.js, CSS, HTML5, Python, Matlab, Arduino, PostgreSQL, Mongo DB
- Libraries & Frameworks: Express, React, Django, Bootstrap, Sequelize, Mongoose, Socket.io
- Management: Trello, Salesforce, Quickbooks, Zapier, Slack, Github, Heroku, Mongo Atlas
- Methodologies: REST, OOP, MVC, User Stories, Responsive Design
- Other: MIG/TIG Welding, Carpentry, Metalwork, Rapid Prototyping, CAD